— SHAIVEE NARULA .— MENTAL HEALTH PROFESSIONAL

CONTACT



+91 9717413448



shaiveenarula0830@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shaive



LinkedIn Profile:

e-narula-983a0513b

PROFILE

Mental Health professional with an experience in school counseling, working with prison inmates, underprivileged population and children.

Strong community and social work/volunteering background, currently pursuing M.Sc. in Psychology specializing in Counseling Psychology from CHRIST (Deemed to be University) Bangalore.

Skilled in communication, interpersonal systems, organisation and management with the ability to think creatively as well as critically across situations and conditions.

SKILLS

- **COUNSELING SKILLS**
- MULTICULTURAL UNDERSTANDING
- **COMMUNICATION**
- **CREATIVITY**
- **CRITICAL THINKING**
- **ANALYTICAL & PROBLEM SOLVING**
- TIME MANAGEMENT
- **ORGANISATION, PLANNING & STRUCTURING**
- ABILITY TO WORK UNDER PRESSURE
- **BASIC MICROSOFT PROGRAMS**
- **EDITING & PROOFREADING**
- **REPORT WRITING**
- **ENGLISH (WRITTEN & SPOKEN)**
- HINDI (WRITTEN & SPOKEN)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant (Intern)

Tata Institute of Social Sciences (TISS), Mumbai (School of Human Ecology)

June 2020 - Present

Unpacking the Covid'19 Effect: A Research Project by TISS Mumbai, to track distress and inform interventions/policy decisions in dealing with the pandemic.

School Counselor (Intern)

Ravindra Bharathi Global School, Bengaluru

November 2019 - March 2020

Providing counseling services to the school.

Individual sessions with students as well as teachers.

Psychoeducation.

Career counseling (psychoeducation).

Group counseling.

EDUCATION

M.Sc. Counseling Psychology

2018-2020

CHRIST (Deemed to be University)

Post Graduate Diploma

"Psycho-Social Well-being using Multi-Arts and Play"

2018-2019

HEADSTREAMS in association with **CHRIST** (Deemed to be University)

B.A. (H) Psychology

2015-2018

Indraprastha College for WomenDelhi University

Senior Secondary

CBSE Board – 2015 (humanities)

New Era Public School

Psychometric Assessments.

School Counselor (Intern)

Carmel Garden Public School, Bengaluru

June 2019 – September 2019

Providing counseling services to the school.

Individual sessions with students.

Psychoeducation.

Career counseling (psychoeducation).

Psychometric Assessments.

Project Developer

Youth for Mental Health, New Delhi

April 2019 - June 2019

Designing the Summer Internship Program.

Researching different sub-disciplines and areas of benefit for the youth.

Conceptualizing the various needs of the organisation into the frame of the program.

Brainstorming and building on the content for the project.

Delegating the work and supervising the team members.

Shortlisting experts for the various sessions with respect to the field of psychology and other subdisciplines.

Creating the timeline and schedule for the project along with other details.

Planning the execution of the project and logistics.

Intern/Facilitator

Headstreams

July 2018 - March 2019

Involved in Tackle Caravan, which is the children's creative learning and positive mental health program of headstreams.

Facilitated play spaces in the Tackle Caravans and helped in exposing young children from underprivileged backgrounds to mediums such as reading, theatre, arts, etc.

Core Team Member & Organizing Team Member

India's First Mental Health Festival

Mental Health Foundation (India), AIIMS, Delhi

June 2017 – October 2017

Content Creation.

Managing human resources.

Registrations coordinator.

Overseeing the organisation, planning, management and execution of the program.

Project In-Charge (Community work Coordinator)

Community Project, Kirti Nagar Mental Health Foundation (India)

January 2017 – June 2017

Heading and coordinating various training and mental health programs.

Conducting Public awareness programs, Client registration and taking case history of clients.

Setting up and successfully executing mental health camps for the underprivileged in rural areas.

Maintaining the follow up visits for proper treatment.

Overall organisation and management of the different programs.

Maintaining records of the clients and other documentation work.

Assigning and delegating work to team mates as well as volunteers and supervising them for their assigned tasks.

Taking feedback of the entire program and implementing required changes.

Crew Member

Mental Health Conclave – Psychological First Aid Mental Health Foundation (India)

September 2016 – October 2016

Held various responsibilities as registrations, campus ambassador, crowd management and maintaining logistics.

Intern

International Bridges to Justice (IBJ), Delhi Prisons (Tihar Jail) and Indraprastha College for Women

January 2017 – May 2017

Providing psychological aid to the prison inmates.

Individual sessions with the inmates, addressing their various needs and requirements and dealing effectively.

Workings towards their positive mental health and well-being.

Bridging the gap between the inmates and the legal system/requirements.

Intern

Mental Health Foundation (India)

June 2016 – July 2016

Attended various workshops and sessions of diverse disciplines within psychology.

Volunteered for community field work.

Assisted in conducting client registration and case history taking.

Assisted in the execution of Mental health camps for the underprivileged.

VOLUNTEER/SOCIAL WORK

Volunteer/Facilitator

Headstreams

July 2018 - March 2019

Volunteer

Indian Aces

September 2017 – August 2018

Volunteer

Community Project of Kirti Nagar, Mental Health Foundation (India)

January 2016 - July 2017

Volunteer

Mental Health Foundation (India)

January 2016 – January 2018